<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-06-02T01:41:19-05:00</updated><id>https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/feed.xml</id><title type="html">APCSP</title><subtitle>Dillon Lee Fastpages Project.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Title</title><link href="https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/2023/06/01/testjava.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title" /><published>2023-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-06-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/2023/06/01/testjava</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exit Ticket</title><link href="https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/2023/05/31/exit-ticket.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exit Ticket" /><published>2023-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/2023/05/31/exit-ticket</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Python 2D Iteration and Animation</title><link href="https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/1.d/2.b/3.b/c3.1/2023/05/16/DS-arrays_lab.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Python 2D Iteration and Animation" /><published>2023-05-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/1.d/2.b/3.b/c3.1/2023/05/16/DS-arrays_lab</id><author><name></name></author><category term="1.D" /><category term="2.B" /><category term="3.B" /><category term="C3.1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Several 2D arrays and Animations hacks are provided to further learn iteration and data in Python. The objective is to build a stronger foundation in iteration and data. Also, it is important to see concepts like printing color and moving objects in terminal, prior to moving to frontend development with JavaScript.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/images/monkeys.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/images/monkeys.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sorting Algorithms</title><link href="https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/2023/05/15/DS-sorting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sorting Algorithms" /><published>2023-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/2023/05/15/DS-sorting</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Working with Data Structures and manipulating data.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Analysis Hacks</title><link href="https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/ap%20notes/csp%20assignments/2023/04/29/dataanalysishack.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Analysis Hacks" /><published>2023-04-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dillonlee06.github.io/VSCode-Fastpages-Project/ap%20notes/csp%20assignments/2023/04/29/dataanalysishack</id><author><name></name></author><category term="AP Notes" /><category term="CSP Assignments" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Questions (0.9) What are the two primary data structures in pandas and how do they differ? Series and DataFrame are the two main types of data structures in pandas. While DataFrame is a two-dimensional labeled data structure with columns of potentially different data types, similar to a spreadsheet or SQL table, Series is a one-dimensional labeled array that can hold any data type. How do you read a CSV file into a pandas DataFrame? Use the read_csv() function offered by pandas to read a CSV file into a pandas DataFrame. The data from the CSV file is returned in a DataFrame object by this function, which accepts the file path of the CSV file as input. How do you select a single column from a pandas DataFrame? You can use bracket notation and provide the name of the column you wish to pick as a string to select a single column from a pandas DataFrame. You can use the syntax df[“column_name”] to choose the column in a DataFrame with the name “column_name,” for instance. How do you filter rows in a pandas DataFrame based on a condition? Boolean indexing can be used to filter rows in a pandas DataFrame according to a criterion. To pick the rows that meet the condition, you can apply a conditional statement to one or more columns in the DataFrame to build a boolean mask. This boolean mask is then passed to the DataFrame’s indexing operator ([]). For instance, the expression df[df[‘column_name’] &gt; 10] will produce a new DataFrame that only contains the rows where the value of “column_name” exceeds 10. How do you group rows in a pandas DataFrame by a particular column? By passing the column name as an argument to the groupby() method of the DataFrame object, you can group the rows in a pandas DataFrame by a certain column. By doing this, a new DataFrameGroupBy object will be created, which you can then modify to aggregate or summarize the data for each group. For instance, df.groupby(‘column_name’) groups the rows of the DataFrame df according to the distinct values in the ‘column_name’ column. How do you aggregate data in a pandas DataFrame using functions like sum and mean? To aggregate data in a pandas DataFrame using functions like sum and mean, you can use the agg() method of the DataFrameGroupBy object returned by groupby(). How do you handle missing values in a pandas DataFrame You can use functions like isna() or isnull() to find missing values in a pandas DataFrame, and then you can use functions like dropna() or fillna() to either remove the rows or fill in the missing values with a specified value or method. How do you merge two pandas DataFrames together? You can use the merge() function supplied by pandas to combine two pandas DataFrames by specifying the columns or indices to merge on, the kind of join to employ, and any extra merge settings. For instance, pd.merge(df1, df2, on=’column_name’, how=’inner’) will use an inner join to combine two DataFrames df1 and df2 on the shared column ‘column_name’. How do you export a pandas DataFrame to a CSV file? To export a pandas DataFrame to a CSV file, you can use the to_csv() method of the DataFrame object and specify the file path and name for the CSV file. What is the difference between a Series and a DataFrame in Pandas? The main difference between a Series and a DataFrame in Pandas is that a Series is a one-dimensional labeled array that can hold any data type, while a DataFrame is a two-dimensional labeled data structure with columns of potentially different data types, similar to a spreadsheet or SQL table.]]></summary></entry></feed>